Guide to the Wendell Holmes Stephenson Papers, 1820-1968
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1921-1968
  - A-K
    - Jackson, Joseph O., 1951 (Box 16)
    - Jackson, W. Turrentine, 1946-1953, undated (Box 16)
    - Jacobs, Wilbur R., 1948-1958, undated (Box 16)
    - Jacobsen, Jerome, V., S. J., 1947-1952 (Box 16)
    - James, Francis G., 1947-1953 (Box 16)
    - Jenkins, William S., 1954-1958, undated (Box 16)
    - Jensen, Merrill, 1947-1952, undated (Box 16)
    - Jernegan, M. W., 1947-1948 (Box 16)
    - Johannen, Robert W., 1950-1953 (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Charles A., 1948-1952 (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Charles S., 1948-1950, undated (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Eldon L., 1950-1956 (Box 16)
    - Johnson, H. M., 1940-1946, undated (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Hildegard Binder, 1947, undated (Box 16)
    - Johnson, J. R., 1948-1949 (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Walter, 1948-1953 (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Z. T., 1927-1931 (Box 16)
    - Johnston, D. J., 1960 (Box 16)
    - Jolliffe, M. F., 1945-1948 (Box 16)
    - Jones, George H., 1950-1952 (Box 16)
    - Jordan, Philip D., 1947-1949 (Box 16)
    - Jordan, Weymouth T., 1946-1963, undated (Box 17)
    - Josephson, Bertha E., 1947-1950, undated (Box 17)
    - Ka-Ky and miscellaneous, 1923-1961, (3 folders) (Box 17)
    - Kaflan, Sidney, 1947-1948 (Box 17)
    - Kaiser, Chester, 1957-1958 (Box 17)
    - Kamm, S. R., 1947-1948 (Box 17)
    - Kane, Harnett T., 1947-1948 (Box 17)
    - Kansas State Historical Society, 1923-1930 (Box 17)
    - Kaplan, Lawrence S., 1948-1949 (Box 17)
    - Kellar, Herbert A., 1943-1953, undated (Box 17)
    - Kelley, Darwin N., 1952, undated (Box 17)
    - Kemble, John H., 1947-1948 (Box 17)
    - Kern, Alexander, 1947-1950, undated (Box 17)
    - Kestenberg, Louis, 1945-1948 (Box 17)
    - Kimura, Kikuya, 1950-1959 (Box 17)
    - Kingery, Lyle B., 1957-1961 (Box 17)
    - Kirby, Thomas A., 1944-1947 (Box 17)
    - Kirkland, Edward C., 1946-1958 (Box 17)
    - Klain, Maurice, 1951 (Box 17)
    - Knoles, George H., 1948-1952 (Box 17)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1947-1952 (Box 17)
    - Koch, Adrienne, 1947-1948 (Box 17)
    - Kohlmeier, A. L., 1946-1948, undated (Box 17)
    - Kramer, Howard, 1947-1948, undated (Box 17)
    - Krenkel, John H., 1947-1948 (Box 17)
    - Krey, A. C., 1951-1952 (Box 17)
    - Kucera, Rita, 1952-1953 (Box 17)
    - Kuhlman, A. F., 1944 (Box 17)
    - Kuritz, Hyman, 1948-1952 (Box 17)
    - Kyte, George W., 1946-1949, undated (Box 17)
  - L-Z
    - La-Ly and miscellaneous, 1929-1962, undated, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - La Marche, Germaine, 1958-1959, undated (Box 18)
    - Lambda Chi Alpha, 1948, undated (Box 18)
    - Lanne, John E., 1948-1950, undated (Box 18)
    - Lathrop, Barnes F., 1950-1959 (Box 18)
    - Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1948 (Box 18)
    - Lavengood, Gene, 1948-1949 (Box 18)
    - Leavitt, Sturgis E., 1947 (Box 18)
    - Le Duc, Thomas, 1949-1957, undated (Box 18)
    - Lee, Charles E., 1954, undated (Box 18)
    - Lee, Ronald F., 1949-1950 (Box 18)
    - Leiby, James, 1951 (Box 18)
    - Leland, Edwin A., Jr., 1952-1953 (Box 18)
    - Leopold, Richard W., 1947-1959, undated (Box 18)
    - Leslie, William R., 1947-1952 (Box 18)
    - Lester, Harry, 1958 (Box 18)
    - Leuchtenburg, William E., 1950-1952, undated (Box 18)
    - Lewis, Anthony M., 1946-1948, undated (Box 18)
    - Library of Congress, 1947-1952, undated (Box 18)
    - Lincoln, Ashbrook, 1948-1949 (Box 18)
    - Link, A. S., 1947-1952 (Box 18)
    - Livermore, Seward W., 1947-1948 (Box 18)
    - Loehr, Rodney C., 1947-1956 (Box 18)
    - Loewenfeld, Eva, 1946, undated (Box 19)
    - London, Lena, 1947-1949 (Box 19)
    - Lord, Clifford L., 1948-1961, undated (Box 19)
    - Lottinville, Savoi, 1946-1958 (Box 19)
    - Loubere, Leo, 1952-1953, undated (Box 19)
    - Louisiana Historical Quarterly, 1930-1933 (Box 19)
    - Louisiana State University, 1929-1945, undated (Box 19)
    - Louisiana State University Press, 1954-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Lowitt, Richard, 1946, undated (Box 19)
    - Luthin, Reinhard H., 1954-1955, undated (Box 19)
    - Lyceum Association, 1947-1948 (Box 19)
    - Lynch, William O., 1924-1956, undated, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Mc, 1929-1968, undated (Box 20)
    - Ma-Mu, 1931-1962, undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - McAnear, Beverly, 1947-1953, undated (Box 20)
    - McAvoy, Thomas T., 1946-1947 (Box 20)
    - McCain, William D., 1943-1949, undated (Box 20)
    - McCaleb, Walter F., 1948 (Box 20)
    - McCloy, Shelby T., 1947-1951 (Box 20)
    - McCutcheon, Roger P., 1944-1953, undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - McDonald, Forrest, 1955-1961, undated (Box 20)
    - McGinty, Garnie W., 1947-1954 (Box 20)
    - McGrane, Reginald C., 1947-1952 (Box 20)
    - McLean, Ross, 1939-1953 (Box 20)
    - McNerney, Chester T., 1952 (Box 20)
    - McReynolds, Edwin C., 1949-1950 (Box 20)
    - MacSwiggan, Amelia E., 1949-1950 (Box 20)
    - Macmillan Company, 1946-1952, undated (Box 20)
    - Main, Jackson T., 1952 (Box 20)
    - Malone, Dumas, 1945-1963 (Box 20)
    - Mamatey, Victor S., 1952 (Box 20)
    - Mandel, Bernard, 1947-1953 (Box 20)
    - Mann, Arthur, 1949-1950 (Box 21)
    - Manning, Thomas G., 1952 (Box 21)
    - March, David D., 1952 (Box 21)
    - Marsh, Philip M., 1946-1948 (Box 21)
    - Martin, S. Walter, 1947-1957 (Box 21)
    - Martin, Thomas P., 1945-1952 (Box 21)
    - Mason, John B., 1942 (Box 21)
    - Masson, Margaret, 1962-1963 (Box 21)
    - Masterson, W. H., 1953-1960, undated (Box 21)
    - Matthews, Joseph J., 1948-1954 (Box 21)
    - Malin, James C., 1943-1948, undated (Box 21)
    - Maunder, Elwood, R. (Forest History Society), 1957-1962, undated, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Mattes, Merrill, J., 1948-1949, undated (Box 21)
    - Maxwell, Robert S., 1948-1960 (Box 21)
    - Mayo, Bernard, 1944-1962 (Box 21)
    - Mencken, H. L., 1948 (Box 21)
    - Mendelson, Wallace, 1952 (Box 21)
    - Menig, Paul H., 1952 (Box 21)
    - Meriwether, R. L., 1945-1952 (Box 21)
    - Merk, Frederick, 1947-1950, undated (Box 21)
    - Merrill, Horace S., 1951-1952 (Box 21)
    - Merrill, Louis T., 1946-1948, undated (Box 22)
    - Metzler, Charles H., 1949-1952 (Box 22)
    - Mexican Council for Historical Research, 1949, undated (Box 22)
    - Miller, Clifford R., 1961 (Box 22)
    - Milne, Taylor, 1960 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1944 (Box 22)
    - Mississippi Valley Historical Association:
      - 1941-1944, undated (Box 22)
      - Cleveland Meeting, 1958 (Box 22)
      - Detroit Meeting, 1960-1961 (Box 22)
      - Programs, 1956-1957, undated (Box 22)
      - St. Louis meeting, 1955, Apr. 28-30 (Box 22)
    - Mitchell, George, 1946-1958 (Box 22)
    - Moe, Henry Allen, 1956-1957 (Box 22)
    - Moffit, A., 1945-1953 (Box 22)
    - Monaghan, J., 1945-1958 (Box 22)
    - Mood, Fulmer, 1952-1954 (Box 22)
    - Mooney, Chase C., 1946-1963 (Box 22)
    - Moore, A. B., 1944-1953 (Box 22)
    - Moore, Arthur K., 1947-1950 (Box 22)
    - Moore, Margaret Stephenson, 1941-1963, undated (Box 22)
    - Moore, Preston, 1950-1952 (Box 22)
    - Morgan, Edmund S., 1948-1951 (Box 22)
    - Morgan, Tom, 1955-1968, undated (Box 22)
    - Mott, F. L., 1947-1951 (Box 22)
    - Mouch, Mildred A., 1946-1948 (Box 22)
    - Mowry, George E., 1946-1953 (Box 22)
    - Muir, Andrew Forest, 1947-1948 (Box 22)
    - Mullett, Charles F., 1956 (Box 23)
    - Murdoch, Richard K., 1948 (Box 23)
    - Na-Nu, 1947-1966, undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Nagengast, Lt. William E., 1951-1953, undated (Box 23)
    - Naroll, Raoul S., 1952 (Box 23)
    - Nash, Gerald, 1952 (Box 23)
    - Nash, Lee, 1958-1967, undated (Box 23)
    - National Archives, 1945-1950 (Box 23)
    - Nau, John F., 1948-1956 (Box 23)
    - Neu, Irene D., 1951-1953, undated (Box 23)
    - Nichols, E. J., 1952 (Box 23)
    - Nichols, Jeannette P., 1947-1957 (Box 23)
    - Nichols, Roy F., 1947-1961 (Box 23)
    - Nigro, Felix A., 1948-1949 (Box 23)
    - Noble, Stuiart G., 1948-1949 (Box 23)
    - Norris, Joe L., 1949-1951 (Box 23)
    - Norton, Howard M., 1948 (Box 23)
    - Nuhrah, Arthur J., 1949-1965, undated (Box 23)
    - Nutting, Sinclair H., 1950 (Box 23)
    - O, 1941-1961, undated (Box 23)
    - Olson, James C., 1946-1956 (Box 23)
    - Osborn, George C., 1941-1968, undated (Box 23)
    - Osmer, William A., 1958 (Box 23)
    - Ostrander, Gilman M., 1951-1957, undated (Box 23)
    - Overdyke, W. Darrell, 1930-1952 (Box 23)
    - Overton, R. C., 1946-1951 (Box 23)
    - Owsley, Frank L., 1946-1953 (Box 23)
    - Oxford University Press, 1947-1953 (Box 23)
    - Pa-Ph, 1946-1960, undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Pi-Pu, 1945-1959 (Box 24)
    - Paine, Mr. and Mrs. Clarence S., 1946-1953, undated, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - Palais, Hyman, 1947-1948 (Box 24)
    - Parker, W. Vann, 1946-1957 (Box 24)
    - Patrick, Rembert W., 1948-1965 (Box 24)
    - Patton, James W., 1944-1962 (Box 24)
    - Pearce, Haywood J., Jr., 1946 (Box 24)
    - Pelzer, Louis, 1945-1947 (Box 24)
    - Pelzer Prize Committee, 1952-1953, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - Pennington, Edgar L., 1951 (Box 24)
    - Perkins, Dexter, 1947-1952 (Box 24)
    - Peterson, H.C., 1948-1951 (Box 24)
    - Peterson, K. S., 1951 (Box 24)
    - Peterson, Virgil V., 1947-1953 (Box 24)
    - Peterson, William J., 1944-1953 (Box 24)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1949-1952 (Box 24)
    - Phillips, George L., 1951 (Box 24)
    - Phillips, Harlan, 1950 (Box 24)
    - Phinney, Sterl, 1958-1957, undated (Box 24)
    - Pi Gamma Mu, 1931, undated (Box 24)
    - Picket, Frances, 1959-1962 (Box 24)
    - Pierce, Bessie, 1946-1950 (Box 24)
    - Pierce, Harry, 1947, 1951 (Box 24)
    - Pierson, G. W., 1946-1947 (Box 24)
    - Pinkney, David H., 1952 (Box 24)
    - Political Science Department, 1947 (Box 25)
    - Pomeroy, Earl S., 1947-1963, undated, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Pool, William C., 1949 (Box 25)
    - Posey, Walter B., 1944-1957 (Box 25)
    - Powell, John H., 1948-1949, undated (Box 25)
    - Power, R. L., 1948-1952 (Box 25)
    - Pratt, Julius W., 1947-1952 (Box 25)
    - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1944-1954 (Box 25)
    - Press Notices, 1945-1949 (Box 25)
    - Postell, William D., 1940-1953 (Box 25)
    - Potter, David M., 1947-1952, undated (Box 25)
    - Pressly, Thomas J., 1950 (Box 25)
    - Prichard, Walter, 1927-1931 (Box 25)
    - Pride, Ellen Perry, 1946-1947 (Box 25)
    - Primavera Press, Inc., 1947-1948 (Box 25)
    - Primm, James N., 1952 (Box 25)
    - Princeton University Press, 1947-1956 (Box 25)
    - Pritchett, John Perry, 1947-1950 (Box 25)
    - Prucha, Francis P., 1952-1953 (Box 25)
    - Que-Qui, 1947-1952 (Box 25)
    - Quint, Howard H., 1947-1952 (Box 25)
    - Ra-Ry, 1931-1963, undated, (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - Raab, Kenneth D., 1948 (Box 26)
    - Rae, John B., 1948 (Box 26)
    - Raines, I. I., 1953 (Box 26)
    - Ramke, Diedrich, 1948-1950 (Box 26)
    - Ramsdell, Charles W., 1934-1943, (3 folders) (Box 26)
    - Randall, Edwin T., 1950-1952 (Box 26)
    - Randall, J. G., 1946-1951 (Box 26)
    - Raney, William F., 1949-1953 (Box 26)
    - Rassekh, Nosratollah, 1964-1966, undated (Box 26)
    - Rayback, Joseph G., 1948-1950 (Box 26)
    - Recktenwald, Lester N., 1949 (Box 26)
    - Reese, Seward, 1958-1960 (Box 26)
    - Research Council--Tulane University, 1946-1949 (Box 26)
    - Reynolds, A. W., 1944-1956 (Box 26)
    - Richardson, Rupert N., 1947-1948 (Box 26)
    - Richardson, Walter, 1943-1956, undated (Box 26)
    - Richmire, George L., 1948, undated (Box 26)
    - Riddell, Katharine C., 1948 (Box 26)
    - Riddle, Donald W., 1947-1953 (Box 26)
    - Riegel, Robert E., 1946-1951 (Box 26)
    - Rifkin, Lester Harvey, 1947-1950 (Box 26)
    - Riley, John E., 1954 (Box 26)
    - Rister, Carl Coke, 1946-1954, undated (Box 26)
    - Robbins, Roy M., 1947-1962 (Box 26)
    - Robert, Joe C., 1944-1952 (Box 27)
    - Roberts, Ella S., 1947-1949 (Box 27)
    - Roberts, Horace G., 1947-1952 (Box 27)
    - Robinson, Shirley M., 1952-1953 (Box 27)
    - Robison, Dan, 1945-1947 (Box 27)
    - Rodriguez, Mario, 1952-1960 (Box 27)
    - Roelofs, Vernon W., 1948-1950 (Box 27)
    - Roland, Charles P., 1952-1953 (Box 27)
    - Roper, Laura Wood, 1951-1952 (Box 27)
    - Roseboom, Eugene H., 1947-1952 (Box 27)
    - Rosengarten, A. G., 1947-1948 (Box 27)
    - Roske, Ralph J., 1949-1951 (Box 27)
    - Rossman, Kenneth R., 1948-1949 (Box 27)
    - Ruchames, Louis, 1950-1951 (Box 27)
    - Ruetten, Richard T., 1959-1964 (Box 27)
    - Ruiz, Ramon, 1956-1958, undated (Box 27)
    - Russ, William A., Jr., 1945-1950 (Box 27)
    - Russell, J. C., 1947-1952, undated (Box 27)
    - Rutherford, W. D., 1961 (Box 27)
    - Sa-Sw, 1923-1962, undated, (4 folders) (Box 27)
    - Sabatier, Ada M., 1948 (Box 27)
    - Salem, Samuel E., 1952-1955 (Box 27)
    - Saloutos, Theodore, 1945-1947, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Salvin, Marina, 1949 (Box 27)
    - Saturday Review of Literature, 1948-1950 (Box 28)
    - Savage, J. H. B., 1959-1960 (Box 28)
    - Savelle, Max, 1947-1957 (Box 28)
    - Saveth, Edward N., 1948-1953 (Box 28)
    - Schauinger, J. Herman, 1948-1949 (Box 28)
    - Scheips, Paul J., 1950-1951 (Box 28)
    - Schell, Herbert S., 1946-1953 (Box 28)
    - Scheps, Clarence, 1948-1951 (Box 28)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1946-1948 (Box 28)
    - Schmidt, L. B., 1947-1952, undated (Box 28)
    - Schorer, C. E., 1950 (Box 28)
    - Schutz, John A., 1954-1957 (Box 28)
    - Scott, Franklin D., 1944-1959 (Box 28)
    - Scott, Sterling, 1949-1953, undated (Box 28)
    - Scribner, Charles and Sons, 1947-1952 (Box 28)
    - Searcy, Elisabeth, 1941-1956, undated (Box 28)
    - Sears, Aflred B., 1948-1952 (Box 28)
    - Sears, Louis Martin, 1950 (Box 28)
    - Selby, John Edward, 1959-1961 (Box 28)
    - Sellers, James L., 1944-1953 (Box 28)
    - Seymour, Harold, 1951-1952 (Box 28)
    - Shafer, Boyd C., 1948-1962 (Box 28)
    - Shanahan, William O., 1961-1962, undated (Box 28)
    - Shanks, Henry T., 1947-1951 (Box 28)
    - Shannon, Fred A., 1949-1953, undated (Box 28)
    - Sharp, Paul F., 1950-1952, undated (Box 28)
    - Shaw, A. M., 1949, undated (Box 28)
    - Shaw, William W., 1947 (Box 28)
    - Sheehan, Donald, 1953 (Box 28)
    - Shepperson, George, 1952-1953 (Box 28)
    - Shideler, James H., 1948 (Box 28)
    - Shoemaker, Floyd, 1946-1950, undated (Box 28)
    - Shottenhamel, George, 1951 (Box 28)
    - Shryock, Richard H., 1947-1952 (Box 29)
    - Shugg, Roger W., 1945-1961 (Box 29)
    - Silin, Charles I., 1947-1951 (Box 29)
    - Silver, James W., 1944-1963 (Box 29)
    - Simkins, Francis B., 1943-1947, undated (Box 29)
    - Simmons, George E., 1946-1947 (Box 29)
    - Simms, Henry, 1947-1948 (Box 29)
    - Simpson, Albert F., 1947-1952 (Box 29)
    - Sigband, Norman B., 1947 (Box 29)
    - Sitterson, J. Carlyle, 1948-1953, undated (Box 29)
    - Skipper, O. C., 1945-1948 (Box 29)
    - Smith, Charles E., 1945-1955, undated (Box 29)
    - Smith, Culver H., 1947 (Box 29)
    - Smith, Dwight L, 1948-1949 (Box 29)
    - Smith, Charles J., 1947, undated (Box 29)
    - Smith, Henry Nash, 1946-1954, undated (Box 29)
    - Smith, James M., 1952 (Box 29)
    - Smith, Joe Patterson, 1946-1948 (Box 29)
    - Smith, Peter, Publishing, 1950-1952 (Box 29)
    - Smith, Robert W., 1962-1963, undated (Box 29)
    - Smith, William E., 1948, 1953 (Box 29)
    - Smylie, Patricia, 1950-1953 (Box 29)
    - Snell, John L., 1949-1955 (Box 29)
    - Snipes, David Franklin, 1948-1949 (Box 29)
    - Snow, Vernon F., 1959-1961 (Box 29)
    - Snyder, Louis L., 1956-1959, undated (Box 29)
    - Social Science Conference--Tulane, 1947-1958, undated (Box 29)
    - Somit, Albert, 1947-1948 (Box 30)
    - Sons of the American Revolution, 1952 (Box 30)
    - Southampton, University of London: Anglo-American History Conference, 1957-1961, undated (Box 30)
    - Southern Biography Series, 1942-1944 (Box 30)
    - Southern Historical Association:
      - 1941-1963, undated, (3 folders) (Box 30)
      - Committee Memberships, 1944, Jan. (Box 30)
      - Meetings, 1947-1949, undated (Box 30)
      - Programs of Annual Meetings, 1950-1957 (Box 30)
    - Southern Humanities Council: Committee on Research Projects, 1948-1949, undated (Box 30)
    - Southwood, Mildred, 1949 (Box 30)
    - Spiro, R. H., Jr., 1952-1953 (Box 30)
    - Staiger, C. Bruce, 1949-1950 (Box 30)
    - Stampp, Kenneth M., 1948-1960 (Box 30)
    - Starkweather, E. Ann, 1957-1962 (Box 30)
    - Starlin, Glenn, 1957-1958 (Box 30)
    - Starr, Chester G., Jr., 1949-1950 (Box 30)
    - State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1947-1952, undated (Box 30)
    - Stavisky, Leonard, 1948-1949 (Box 30)
    - Stephens, I. K., 1947 (Box 30)
    - Stephenson, Wendell H., 1932-1934 (Box 30)
    - Stephenson family, 1943-1946, undated (Box 30)
    - Stern, Alfred K., 1945-1952, undated (Box 30)
    - Stewart, Edgar I., 1947-1955 (Box 30)
    - Stibbs, John H., 1951-1953 (Box 30)
    - Still, Bayrd, 1946-1958 (Box 30)
    - Stipp, John L., 1950 (Box 30)
    - Sulzby, James F., Jr., 1947-1949 (Box 30)
    - Summers, Festus P., 1947-1951 (Box 31)
    - Summersell, Charles G., 1956-1958 (Box 31)
    - Swearingen, Mack, 1948-1952 (Box 31)
    - Sweet, James Stouder, 1948-1951 (Box 31)
    - Sweet, William W., 1946-1949 (Box 31)
    - Swint, Henry M., 1947-1952 (Box 31)
    - Sydnor, Charles S., 1945-1954 (Box 31)
    - Sydenham, M. J., 1959-1960, undated (Box 31)
    - Syracuse University: Maxwell Graduate School of Citizenship and Public Affairs, 1947, 1950, undated (Box 31)
    - Ta-Ty, 1948-1960, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Tait, Samuel W., 1947-1950 (Box 31)
    - Tansill, Charles C., 1948, undated (Box 31)
    - Tarkow-Naamani, Israel, 1947 (Box 31)
    - Taylor, Garland F., 1946-1953, undated (Box 31)
    - Taylor, George Rogers, 1949 (Box 31)
    - Taylor, Rhea, 1946-1948 (Box 31)
    - Tegeder, Vincent G., 1946-1948, undated (Box 31)
    - Terhune, Thorton, 1941-1950 (Box 31)
    - Thomas, Benjamin P., 1952-1953 (Box 31)
    - Thomas, L. G., 1958-1959 (Box 31)
    - Thomas, Mary E., 1951-1952 (Box 31)
    - Thompson, Arthur W., 1950 (Box 31)
    - Thompson, Robert L., 1947-1952, undated (Box 31)
    - Thompson, Stith, 1948 (Box 31)
    - Thornbrough, Conway D., 1950-1955 (Box 31)
    - Thornbrough, Gayle, 1945-1948 (Box 31)
    - Thornton, H. J., 1947-1949 (Box 31)
    - Throckmorton, Arthur L., 1960-1962 (Box 31)
    - Tilley, Winthrop, 1949 (Box 31)
    - Tillapaugh, James, undated (Box 31)
    - Tindall, George B., 1951-1967, undated (Box 31)
    - Tinling, Marion, 1946-1947 (Box 32)
    - Toppino, Florence W., 1948-1953, undated (Box 32)
    - Torch Press, 1946-1953, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - Toy, Eckard, V., Jr., 1958-1960, undated (Box 32)
    - Tregle, Joseph G., 1947-1959 (Box 32)
    - Tryon, Warren S., 1947-1958 (Box 32)
    - Tucker, William P., 1945-1947, undated (Box 32)
    - Tulane University Book Store, 1947-1949, undated (Box 32)
    - Turner, Arlin, 1942-1959, undated (Box 32)
    - Turner, Charles W., 1947-1952 (Box 32)
    - Tuthill, Edward, 1924-1931 (Box 32)
    - Twiddle, Twaddle and Bosh, 1942-1943, undated (Box 32)
    - Uk-Ut, 1924-1967, undated (Box 32)
    - United States Educational Foundation in India, 1957-1963 (Box 32)
    - University of Birmingham, 1947-1951, undated (Box 32)
    - University of Kentucky, 1925-1946 (Box 33)
    - University of Michigan, 1926-1930 (Box 33)
    - University of Oregon, 1957-1968, undated (Box 33)
    - Urban, C. Stanley, 1946-1958 (Box 33)
    - Usher, Roland G., Jr., 1949-1951, undated (Box 33)
    - Va-Vo and miscellaneous V, 1929-1962, undated (Box 33)
    - Valentin, Veit, 1947 (Box 33)
    - Vallas, Elizabeth J., 1952-1953 (Box 33)
    - Van Alstyne, Richard W., 1949-1953 (Box 33)
    - Vance, Rupert, 1946-1954 (Box 33)
    - Vander Velde, Lewis G., 1948-1949 (Box 33)
    - Vandiver, Frank, 1947-1961, undated, (4 folders) (Box 33)
    - Varg, Paul A., 1947-1958 (Box 33)
    - Vaughn, Thomas, 1955-1961 (Box 33)
    - Venkataramani, M. S., 1955-1967, undated (Box 33)
    - Versteeg, Clarence L., 1951-1963, undated (Box 33)
    - Vinson, J. Chal. 1951-1952 (Box 33)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1950-1953, undated (Box 33)
    - Volwiler, A. T., 1946-1952 (Box 33)
    - Voorhis, Manning C., 1947-1952 (Box 33)
    - Wa-Wy, 1943-1963, undated, (4 folders) (Box 34)
    - Waggaman, Jane F., 1946-1949, undated (Box 34)
    - Wall, Bennett, 1946-1959, (3 folders) (Box 34)
    - Wallace, Sarah A., 1948-1950 (Box 34)
    - Waller, G. M., 1953-1961 (Box 34)
    - Walz, Vina, 1951, undated (Box 34)
    - Wang, Gung-Hsing, 1951-1957 (Box 34)
    - Ward, Margaret, 1960-1962 (Box 34)
    - Ware, Lowry, 1954 (Box 34)
    - Warner, Donald F., 1947-1953 (Box 34)
    - Warner, Earl E., 1947 (Box 34)
    - Warren, Harris G., 1946-1958, undated (Box 34)
    - Warrick, Clyde C., 1944 (Box 34)
    - Watson, Richard L., 1946-1963, undated (Box 34)
    - Weaver, Blanche, 1947-1948 (Box 34)
    - Weir, LeRoy M., 1946-1947 (Box 34)
    - Weisberger, Bernard A., 1948-1950, undated (Box 34)
    - Weisenburger, Francis P., 1947-1949, undated (Box 34)
    - Welsh, Donald H., 1951-1952 (Box 34)
    - Wharton, V. L., 1947 (Box 35)
    - Whitaker, Arthur P., 1946-1949 (Box 35)
    - White, Eugene E., 1946 (Box 35)
    - White, M. M., 1947-1948 (Box 35)
    - Who's Who in America, 1948-1949, undated (Box 35)
    - Wickersham, Edward D., 1948 (Box 35)
    - Wiley, Bell I., 1946-1952, undated (Box 35)
    - Wilkerson, Marcus M., 1944-1953, undated, (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Wilkinson, Norman B., 1951 (Box 35)
    - Williams, Clanton W., 1947, undated (Box 35)
    - Williams, Mentor L., 1947-1949, undated (Box 35)
    - Williams, Robert W., 1953-1959, undated (Box 35)
    - Williams, T. Harry, 1946-1959, undated (Box 35)
    - Williams, William, 1949-1958, undated (Box 35)
    - Willis, Edward, 1950 (Box 35)
    - Wilson, Charles R., 1947 (Box 35)
    - Wilson, Harold F., 1952 (Box 35)
    - Wilson, Logan, 1946-1948 (Box 35)
    - Wilson, O. Meredith, 1954-1959, undated (Box 35)
    - Winter, Carl G., 1952, undated (Box 35)
    - Winther, Oscar O., 1946-1957 (Box 35)
    - Wish, Harvey, 1941-1952, undated (Box 35)
    - Wittke, Carl, 1946-1953, undated (Box 36)
    - Woody, Robert H., 1944-1964, undated (Box 36)
    - Woodward, C. Vann, 1944-1956 (Box 36)
    - Woolfolk, George H., 1949 (Box 36)
    - Worcester, D. E., 1944-1958 (Box 36)
    - Worley, Ted R., 1950 (Box 36)
    - Worner, Lloyd E., 1949-1950 (Box 36)
    - Wright, Gordon, 1953-1959 (Box 36)
    - Y-Z, 1939-1958 (Box 36)
    - Yale University Press, 1947-1951, undated (Box 36)
    - Yanuck, Julius, 1951-1956 (Box 36)
    - Young, Alfred, 1948-1951 (Box 36)
    - Young, James Harvey, 1950-1952 (Box 36)
    - Younger, Edward, 1950-1957 (Box 36)
    - Ziegler, James D., 1958-1961, undated (Box 36)
    - Zorn, Roman C., 1948-1953 (Box 36)
    - Zornow, William F., 1948-1955 (Box 36)
- Writings and Speeches, 1922-1966
  The bulk consists of Stephenson's articles, speeches, book reviews, and related source material concerning Southern history and occasionally American and European history. Coverage begins with his college education and extends throughout his professional career. Arranged alphabetically including categories for book reviews and speeches.
  - Bibliography of Publications (Box 37)
  - Address at Southern Historical Association, ca. 1960, on Southern Historiography (Box 37)
  - Amos Lane Advocate of Western Democracy, 1930 (Box 37)
  - Anglo-American Diplomatic Relations of the Civil War, Locke Prize Essay, 1922 (Box 37)
  - Anglo-French Relations, 1870-1914, 1926, undated (Box 37)
  - Ante-Bellum New Orleans as an Agricultural Focus, 1941 (Box 37)
  - Avenue to Now, 1950 (Box 37)
  - The Bagdad Railway, undated (Box 37)
  - Book Reviews, 1933-1957, (7 folders) (Box 37)
  - Book Reviews, 1958-1963, undated, (3 folders) (Box 38)